We can now describe the main step that introduces error, meaning quantization.
我们现在可以开始描述会引起误差的主要步骤 那就是量化
And it's also the step that I figured out was to compress a lot.
我要指出 这也是进行很大压缩的一步
Without quantization, we won't be able to compress too much.
没有量化 我们不可能做到很大压缩
We will be able to compress, but not as much as we see in our digital comments.
我们可以做压缩 但是不会像在数码相机里看到的那么多
So basically, we have the forward transform, which we have seen.
基本上我们采用了之前见过的正变换
We have these, we have seen earlier, but now we're going to describe the
这个之前已经见过了 但是现在我们将要描述量化
quantization. So let's talk about it.
让我们先说这个
And we have actually already seen quantization when we started talking, the
实际上我们之前就已经见过 量化
very early weeks of this class, but let's just describe it in detail in the context
就在本课刚开始几个星期的时候 那么我们要在 JPEG 压缩的过程中
of JPEG compression. So, remember, we started from an eight by
详细讲解量化 所以请记住 我们是从一个
eight image, and we have that on transform.
8 x 8 图像开始的 而且我们已经将它进行变换了
And what I'm going to represent here are the transform coefficients.
我将要在这里展示变换系数
So just, in the previous video, we saw that we actually have the transform
在之前的视频中 我们实际上已经见过变换系数了
coefficients. And we get them as a double sum, with sum
我们用二重求和得到变换系数
over the X, with sum over the Y, with sum over coordinates of the image.
通过沿X轴求和 再沿Y轴求和 即沿图像的坐标轴进行求和
And we're basically summing the image. This is the image,
我们将图片“加”起来 这个是图片
and we have, basically, the cosine basis.
接着我们有余弦基函数
So that's how we got to these coefficients that we represent here.
这就是如何得到展示在这里的这些系数的
We start from an eight by eight, and we get eight by eight coefficients.
我们由一个 8 x 8 的图像得到了一个 8 x 8 的系数矩阵
So we have kind of an image in a different domain, in the cosine domain.
所以我们在不同的域 在余弦域得到了一幅图像
So what we have here are different things that we could do to those coefficients.
我们现在可以对这些系数做不同的事情
Now we are working with coefficients. So for example, we could say that we are
接着我们就要对系数做一定的工作了 举个例子 我们只需要
only going to take coefficients and we'll ignore all these other coefficients.
取这里的系数 忽略其他的系数
We could, that would be very, very simple, sway go to the upper left corner
非常非常地简单 我们可以到左上角
and only use those coefficients, ignore everybody else.
然后只使用这些系数 忽略掉其他的
And I'm going to write in a second what that means.
我将马上写出这代表着什么
We could also do these, which says, somehow, I'm going to say which
我们也可以这样做 以这样的方式
coefficients to take. Those that are shaded, or says 1 are
取用系数 这些带阴影或者说值为1的系数是
going to be coefficients I'm going to send. Those that say 0 or unshaded
将要传输的系数 那些值为0或者说没有阴影的系数
coefficients, I'm not going to send or store.
是不准备传输或存储下来的
Now we can do something else and we can say you know what,
我们还可以做一些其它处理 我们会想
I don't want to, include or discard coefficients.
我并不想计入或者丢弃系数
I want you to take this coefficient up here and represent it with eight bits.
我们要做的是把系数取到这里来并且用8位比特数表示它
So I'm going to let you to do quantization to 256 levels.
这样它的量化级数就为 256
On the other hand, this coefficient that shows up here, so that would be the
另一方面 这里的这个系数
coefficient 07, T-07. I want you to use only one bit.
也就是系数 T(0,7) 我想只用 1个比特位来表示它
So you're going to only be able to represent two different levels for that
所以我们将只能用两个不同级别来表示这个系数
coefficient. And we are going to talk about this in a
接下来我们要说的就是这个
second. Now, what happens when we do
假如我们现在开始量化 会发生什么？
quantization? Remember that F is going to be then
请记住 f(x,y) 接着将要被重建
reconstructed, as we saw in the previous, video, as the sum of T.
就像我们在之前的视频中看到的那样 f(x,y)是T(u,v)求和得到的
The transform coefficients. And we can put R because you remember
T(u,v) 就是变换系数 我们可以在这里使用 r
that the forward and inverse were basically the same.
因为我们知道正变换和反变换是一样的
So this is how we're going to reconstruct our image.
我们就是这样重构图像的
Now if we quantize T we're not going to reconstruct F because we're going to have
现在假如我们要量化T 而不是重构f 因为我们会有
an approximation of T. And then we're going to reconstruct an
一个 T(u,v) 的近似值 接着我们需要重构出
approximation of F. And remember what's happening is this.
f(x,y) 的近似值 请记住这里会发生变化
Our F is a linear combination of the coefficients,
我们所得到的的 f(x,y) 是系数的一个线性组合
either the original coefficients, or the quantized coefficients, a linear
这个系数要么是原始系数 要么是量化后的系数
combination multiplying the bases. And these are the bases.
也就是乘了基函数的线性组合 这些就是所谓的基函数
So here I'm just drawing them in a four by four, but we know that we are talking
我在这里把它们弄成了 4 x 4 的图像块 但是我们知道所讨论的是
eight by eight. So this top coefficient basically says
8 x 8 的图像 所以这个顶部的系数主要是用来说明
how much of this basis we are going to be using.
我们接着要使用多少这些基函数
And you can say, you know what? Maybe our visual perception is such that
可以这样说 或许我们的视觉感知是
if instead of what I wanted to use, which is 7.7 times these bases.
假如本来我要使用 7.7乘以这些基函数
Maybe if I do 7.5 it's not such a big deal, and my visual system won't perceive
或许我最后只乘以了7.5 却不会有很大影响 而且我的视觉系统
the difference. So that's idea of quantization, to
不会察觉到有什么不同 这就是量化的思想
basically round or say, if I put slightly a different number of this component,
量化主要思想是数值修约 或者说 如果让这个分量里的值稍稍变化一点
whatever component TUV represents, it might not be such a big deal in the
无论T(u,v)这部分代表的是什么 在重构时都不会产生太大影响
reconstruction. And we're going to see that.
一会儿我们就会看到
Now, remember why are we doing quantization?
现在大家还记得我们为什么要做量化吗？
We are doing quantization because we are going to do Huffman coding after that.
我们要做量化是因为之后要进行霍夫曼编码
And remember, in Huffman coding, we want a non-uniform distribution.
请记住一点 在霍夫曼编码里 我们需要非均匀分布
We want some coefficients to appear a lot,
一些系数会出现很多次
so we're going to give a short code, and some coefficients to appear not much,
所以我们将对其进行短编码 而一些系数出现次数并不多
so we can give them a long code. for example, if we quantize a load,
那我们就给它们进行长编码 举个例子 如果我们量化得很多
we might find out that 7, 8, 9, 10 all become 0.
我们也许发现7、8、9、10都会变成0
And then we're going to be able to basically compress a lot and we're
然后我们就能压缩很多
going to see a bit more examples of that in the next transparencies. Now,
在接下来的幻灯片中可以看到一些更多的例子
this is the basic idea. As I say, we are going to quantize, we
这个式子就是量化的基本思想 正如我所说 我们准备开始量化了
are going to change the coefficients that hopefully we are not going to notice
我们需要改变一些系数 希望能够不被注意到
that. Now there is something I want to call
现在我要提醒大家注意的是
your attention, something which is very smartly done in
有些可以在JPEG里巧妙地得到的东西
JPEG. If we just do quantization, we still have
如果只是去做量化 我们仍然需要
to send an eight by eight matrix of quantized, transformed values, means I
传输一个量化后的8x8变换值矩阵 这意味着
have to send 64 numbers. Now I started, let's say, from an image
我们需要传输64个数 现在我们有一个
that has eight bits per pixel, 256 gray levels.
每像素8比特 256个灰度级的图片
Then I need to send each one of these, even if I'm going to use only one bit, as
接着我们需要传输这里的每一个值 即使像这样只用一个比特
it says here. So I started from eight bits, and I can
所以我们从8比特开始
use one, then I can only compress eight to one.
然后只使用1比特 以8比1压缩
I have to basically send you that value. JPEG say something very smart.
我们只要传输那个值就可以了 JPEG很巧妙地表示了一些东西
As we're going to see in a second, the top region is going to use as its
接下来我们要看到的是 顶部区域将使用这里的代替值
representation here, more bits. The quantization is going to be more
比特数越多 量化效果就越好
fine. In the lower corner here, JPEG is
在这里的底角部分
going to say, you know what? I'm going to do very, very drastic
JPEG将会表示出… 我将要做一些非常非常剧烈的量化
quantizations. So drastic, that a lot of the TUV, the
实在是太剧烈了 导致T(u,v)中的很多系数
coefficients would become 0. So JPEG is not going to encode, is not
都会变成0 所以JPEG并不用来编码
going to store this, then this, then this, to UV.
它不是先存这个T(u,v) 再存这个 接着这个
It's going to actually go in a zigzag fashion.
它实际上是按照锯齿形的方式来进行的
It's going to say, okay first, I'm going to just do a convention.
这意味着 好吧 首先我们做个约定
The first coefficient you see is this, which is T00.
在这里看到的第一个系数是T(0,0)
The second coefficient you see is this one, which is T01.
第二个系数是T(0,1)
The third coefficient you see is this one, which is T10, okay?
第三个系数是T(1,0) 对吧？
So you're going to be, basically be encoding the quantized 0, 0.
所以你要做的是编码量化后的(0,0)
Then you're going to be encoding the quantized 0, 1.
再编码量化后的(0,1)
quantized 1,
再编码量化后的(1,0)
0. And then you keep going in this zigzag
然后就这样按照锯齿形的方式往下进行
fashion. Now, why is that important?
为什么这么做很重要？
As I say, a lot of these are going to become 0.
正如我之前说的 这里的很多值都会变成0
Their value is going to be 0, after we do a very strong quantization there.
在我们做了很强的量化以后 它们的值都会变成0
So when JPEG arrives to a certain coefficient, and sees that everybody else
所以当JPEG进行到某一个系数的时候 发现后续其他所有系数
that comes after becomes 0, it just puts one signal that says end.
都变成了0 我们只需用一个信号来表明结束
And if the nth is here, meaning everybody here is 0, then I save a lot of bits.
假如这第n个数在这里 就代表着这里的所有数都是0 那我们就能省下很多比特
It's still sending one bit for each, let's say, to say, 0, 0, 0, we're
它还是按照每个比特来传输 比方说 用0、0、0来表示
basically saying one end, and that means, to the end of my block, to the end of my
本质上是在表示结束 这意味着这一块结束了
eight by eight transform coefficients, everybody became 0.
这个8x8传输系数矩阵结束了 所有系数都变成了0
And that's a very smart thing, and that's what allow us to go beyond eight to one
这确实很巧妙 通过这个可以让我们达到超过8比1的压缩比
and to very, very high compression ratios.
甚至是非常非常高的压缩比
And the more you're quantizing this region, the earlier this end symbol will
而且这个区域量化的越多 这个结束符号出现的越早
appear. So that's the basic idea of quantization,
所以这就是量化的基本思想
but let's just see how we do it. So, a very simple form of quantization is
让我们来看一下如何做到的 量化的一个非常简单的方式是
what we have here, and that's called uniform quantization, and this is
像这样的均匀量化
basically what jpeg is doing. And, it's saying, okay you take your
这也是JPEG主要所做的工作 这就是说 取了系数以后
coefficients. I want to do uniform quantization in the
需要做均匀量化
sense that, let's just pick for example, this interval.
在某种意义上来说 举个例子 这个区间
It's in, everything that falls in here. Every coefficient that has values between
所有落在这里面的数
this point and this point I'm going to represent with this.
每个值落在这一点和这一点之间的系数 都可以用它来表示
So that's basically very important. So now I'm going to help halfman coding.
这就很重要了 现在我们要开始哈夫曼编码
No matter what you are, you're going to be represented by one number.
无论是多少 都得用一个数来代替
So I'm basically going to increase the probability of that number appear.
我们主要做的是增大那个数出现的概率
Instead of having a lot of numbers appear very few times, I have one number appears
我们会把有很多出现次数很少的数
a lot of times. And that's very important as we know, for
替换为一个出现很多次的数 就像我们知道的那样
halfman coding, or for any coder that will show up at the last stage of
这对于压缩最后的哈夫曼编码或者其他任何编码器来说都很重要
compression. Now everything, for example, in this
举个例子 现在所有
interval from here to here would be represented by this value.
落在从这儿到这儿的区间里的系数 都会被表示为这个值
And the way JPEG does that, and many other coders, it's saying, okay,
而且JPEG和许多编码器所做的意味着
I'm going to give you numbers that you're going to scale by that number.
我准备给出一些数让大家按照数的比例 (划分)
Okay? And then just so, basically, it says that
准备好了吗？接下来要说的是T(0,0)
the T00. The T00 is going to be divided by 16.
T(0,0)要被16除
We saw that early on in one of the first videos.
我们在之前最开始的一个视频中见到过
This is going to be rounded, and then it's going to be multiplied by
先要将其取整 然后再次乘以16
16 again, and that basically became my new T00.
乘了以后的值就成为新的T(0,0)
Very simple operation, but very efficient.
这种方法很简单 却很有效
Maybe not ideal, maybe not the best I could do.
或许并不很理想 也并不是最好的方式
But JPEG is motivated as not only by doing good quality but also by
但是JPEG被提倡不仅因为其高性能
simplicity. And we have seen what this makes
同样因为简便性 而且我们能够看到这使得量化如何操作的
proficiencts do. So as we see here, if T00 basically,
所以就像我们看到的那样 如果T(0,0)是
every number. Between zero.
一个0和15之间的任意数
And. Fifteen will become zero with this
通过这种方法都会变成0
operation. If I have seven divided by sixteen, it's
如果我们用7除以16
a number that when I round down, it becomes zero and multiply by sixteen and
将结果向下取整的时候就会变成0 再乘以16以后
it becomes zero, stays zero. So, basically every number here.
它依旧为0 所以 所有在这个区间的数
Became zero. Every number then.
都会变成0 然后所有
Building sixteen. And 31.
在16至31之间的数
Became one. So I'm basically quantizing.
都会变成1 这样就实现了量化。
And I'm helping Huffman to basically have less numbers to send, and also more
我们所做的这些会帮助霍夫曼编码传输更少的数 这些数也更多的浓缩了
concentration. And the more we scale by.
而且这个比例越大
So for example, if we scale by 100, it means every number between 0 and 99 will
举个例子 假如我们按照100的比例 在0到99之间的所有数都会变为0
become zero. So my quantization decision is much more
所以这种量化决策更加显著
broad. So not as fine, but hopefully, if I do it
所以它虽然不是很好 但还是不错的 如果做得正确
correct, I won't notice too much. So that's a basic idea of JPEG
那么就不会察觉到太大的变化 这就是JPEG量化的基本思想
quantization. So, it's going to give and I'm going to
接下来要给大家展示的是
show, that, basic, the default table in jpeg in a second, is going to do this.
这个JPEG里面基础的 默认表格
And remember what I said in the previous slide because you're going to, quantize,
记住我在以前的幻灯片中说过的那些东西 因为我们马上就要开始量化很多数
a lot, the high ones. A lot of these, are going to become 0,
这里面很多都会变成0
and then this, end of block signal is going to be very powerful to compress, a
然后 块结束信号将能够压缩很多
lot of symbols, with a, a lot of coefficients, a lot of TUV.
很多个符号以及很多个系数 很多个T(u,v)
A lot of a, a, transform coefficients with just one symbol.
很多只有一个符号的变换系数
Extremely powerful. So let's just give an example.
压缩的效果都极强 举个例子来说
This is done actually with a previous matrix,
这实际上是用之前的矩阵
and the basic idea, and this is how JPEG basically operates.
和基本思想形成的 这也是JPEG如何压缩的
It's going to do the following. It's going to take this matrix, and I'm
接下来 我会用这个矩阵
going to show the matrix for JPEG in a second, as I say.
然后就像我说的那样用JPEG的方式讲解这个矩阵
And say okay. Let's just do it.
好了，让我们现在来试一下。
Let's just divide by 16, 11, 12, 12, and so on,
我们除以16、11、12、12这样子
ot I can tell you to divide by twice this matrix. So by 32, 22, 24, 24, and so on.
或者说用两倍的这个矩阵来除 就是除以32、22、24、24这样
So, let's see the affects of that. So here we basically progressively are
接着让我们看一下效果 我们逐步所除的矩阵是同一个矩阵
dividing by the same matrix, but scale up and we see how the quality degrades.
只是按比例扩大了而已 我们能看到质量是如何变低的
Of course we're not going to want to do this.
当然我们并不想让图像变成这样
What probably happened here is that we end up multiplying by 32 times Z so we
这个图像效果出现的原因可能是 当我们在将矩阵乘了32次Z以后
end up basically destroying most of the coefficients.
大部分的系数也遭到了破坏
But if we basically don't multiply by too much that matrix so we can scale down,
但是假如我们不把矩阵乘那么多次 而是按比例缩小
divide by 16, divide by 11. Multiply around, multiply back and get
除以16 除以11 先乘再除然后得到
very, very decent quality images. The more we divide, the more we compress.
质量非常非常好的图像 我们除得越多 就压缩的越多
So if we, as we saw in the previous slide, if we're going to divide by two
所以就像在之前的幻灯片里看到的那样 如果我们用2去除的话
we're only rounding basically. If we're going to divide by 100 we're
我们只是在取整 但是如果我们用100去除
basically making these blocks of numbers become all equal or if we want to see
就会使这些块中的数变得全都一样
this in the graph, the larger this is. The more we are quantizing.
或者就像看到这张图 这个越大 量化的就越多
And this is as promised the default table that I think it's going to use or one of
这个就是JPEG准备使用的默认表
the possibilities for the default table. And the reason why I'm showing it to you
也可以说是默认表的一个可能性 我想给大家看这个表的原因在于
is because once again I want to see you I want to show you how increase.
我想再一次给大家看这些数是如何增加的
They're decreased by and there have been a lot of studies on this but still the
它们减少了 虽然对这些做了大量的处理
condensation is uniform. And once again you can basically do
但是压缩依然是均匀的 接着对矩阵又一次做乘法
multiplications of that matrix. So this is what you're going to get with
所以这张图就是我们将会得到的
one scale of that matrix, and then if you scale it more you're going to get, and I
一倍矩阵得到的图像 更大地扩大矩阵倍数 会得到这样的结果
hope you can see the quality, and this is the error,
我希望你能看出它的质量 这是误差
just in case, it's hard for you to see from the image.
从图里很难看出来
But, lets just concentrate on certain regions.
让我们关注一下某些区域
We see here, it looks very nice. So probably, we haven't scaled the
我们来看这里 很不错的样子 很可能是我们没有将量化矩阵划分得很大
quantization matrix too much. Here, we're actually scale it too much,
再看这里就是划分得很大了
and it doesn't look very good. Look at this zoom-in region.
看起来不是很好 把这片区域放大以后再来看一下
It really doesn't look very good. Also here, if you zoom in, you can see
看起来确实不好 还有这里 如果我们把它放大的话 就能够看到
some problems with the image, but not at this scale.
图像上出现了一些问题 但在这种比例的图上却看不见
So, basically, what we have is a quantization matrix that says every one
因此我们具有一个量化矩阵
of the transformed coefficients, TUV.
它用来表示所有变换系数T(u,v)
What do we want to do? Do we want to divide it and round and
我们到底想做的是什么？ 是想除了以后再取整
divide it by five? Or divide it by 100?
然后再除以5？ 还是再除以100？
And the larger the number we divide by, the more error we are producing.
我们除以的数越大 产生的误差也就越大
But of course the more compression. we are doing.
不过我们压缩得也越多
So it's interesting. In some of the software packages that you
所以这很有意思 在一些软件包里
have out there, when you are saving an image, it asks you
当保存一张图像时
for the quality that you want to save your JPEG image with.
它会询问我们想保存的JPEG图像质量
And what it's asking you is basically how much to multiply this quantization
它所询问的其实就是要乘以量化矩阵的倍数大小
matrix. So the quantization matrix is basically,
所以量化矩阵…
in that package, is a fixed matrix. So how are you going to basically
在软件包里 是一个固定矩阵 所以我们如何压缩更多或者更少呢？
compress more or less? By scaling up or down that quantization
答案就是通过按比例扩大或者缩小量化矩阵
matrix. So when it says you want high quality,
所以当表示为我们需要高质量时
it's not, not going to scale by a lot. When it says you want high compression or
并不是需要很大的比例 当表示我们需要高压缩或者低质量时
lower quality, it's going to scale it by a lot.
才是需要很大的比例
And that's how JPEG works. With a very simple,
这就是JPEG如何实现压缩的 它使用一种非常简单的
basically uniform quantization that is done just by scaling and multiplying
均匀量化 通过按比例划分再乘回原来的比例
back. Of course, the multiplication is done at
当然 乘的过程是在解码器中完成的
the decoder. So every number between 0 and 100, if you
在0至100之间的每一个数
scale down 100, between 0 and 99, sorry. If you scale by 100 it's going to be
假如我们将它按100的比例缩减 在0和99之间的 抱歉 假如我们将它按照100的比例来
coded at the zero and then the decoder is going to multiply by 100 to get the
这些数都会被编码为0 接着解码器乘以100以后会重新得到这些数
number back. So that's what JPEG does for quantization
所以这就是JPEG在量化上所做的
and that's where you get the compression. Now, I want to mention that.
通过这些我们可以得到压缩 现在我想提到的一点是
There are techniques and there are theories to try to basically adapt the
有技术和理论能够随着信号的类型尝试调整量化
quantization to the signal type. So, jpeg does a uniform quantization
JPEG采用均匀量化
because it's very simple. You, we don't have to do a uniform
是因为它很简单 我们不需要做均匀量化
quantization. We can have intervals as shown here, that
我们可以构造图中的这些区间
have basically different width. So some regions will be basically, scale
他们的宽度不同 一些区域会比其他的区域划分得更大
more than other regions. That doesn't happen in JPEG. it's
这在JPEG里是不会出现的
uniform. No matter what value is TUV.
JPEG里是均匀的 无论什么T(u,v)的值
You always divide, for a given coefficient position, you always divide
我们总是都要除它 在一个给定的系数位置
by exactly the same number. Now here, depending on what's your input,
我们总要用相同的数去除 看这里 就是根据我们输入的不同
the value your going to be divided by. And that's very important that JPEG
根据我们准备除以的值 JPEG并不这样做 这一点很重要
decided not to do that. Once again in part because of simplicity,
再一次说明部分原因是简便性
but I want to include this chapter in quantization by explaining to you that
我把相关的这一章放在量化里 我想给大家解释一下
you could actually to do better if you were willing to spend a bit more
如果愿意在算法里使用更多的复杂性 那么实际上效果会更好
complexity in your algorithm. And basically there is very nice theory
有一种非常好的关于如何做得更好的理论
on how to do better and that's called the Max-Lloyd Optimal Quantizer.
叫做Max-Lloyd最优量化器
And the basic idea is relatively simple, although computations are not always
其主要思想相对简单 尽管并不总是直接的计算
straightforward. And what they have shown is basically
已经显示的是 请记住
remember, if you want to measure the error as the square difference between a
如果要测量一个给定的像素和其输出像素之间的方差作为误差
given pixel and it's representation, and we talk about the square.
我们要讲的就是这个均方
So that's a way you decide. You say, I want to do the best possible
看大家怎么决定 要在考虑这个误差的情况下
quantizer considering this error. And considering that I have certain
做出最好的量化器 还要考虑到比特数的确切的分配
allocations of bits. Of course, if you say, I don't care how many bits
当然如果不考虑使用比特的多少
are used, then don't quantize at all. That would be basically 0 error.
那就根本不用量化了 自然就会变成零误差了
But if you come and tell me, I can only use, basically.
但是如果我们只能用256级
256 levels. So I can only use eight bits.
那就只能使用8个比特位
So I can only have 256 of these intervals,
只能拥有256个区间
because I need to represent each interval by one of my strings of bits.
因为每个区间都需要用一个位串去表示
And so you predefine the number of levels that you are willing to use, the number
所以我们事先定义好想要使用的级的个数
of intervals, and you predefine this as your error.
即区间的个数 然后预先定义这个作为误差
So you can show that basically what we have to do, and this is very intuitive.
这样就能显示出我们需要去做的 非常的直观
You say, okay, what's the error I am making in every
好了 那什么才是我们在每个区间产生的误差呢？
interval? So you are going in every one of these
在这里的每一个区间
intervals, so I am going to do s sub I minus one over s sub i.
都要从s_(i-1)到s_(i+1)进行积分
That's my integration, and you can show that if this is the error that you care
就是这个积分 大家可以看到假如这就是我们关心的误差
about, then here you have to put s minus,
那么在这里就需要放上s_i 减去
basically it's only S, because I'm going to do an integral, minus T sub I.
事实上只有s 因为接下来要进行积分 s减去t_i
So that's the error. You get S, you represent it with T.
所以这就是误差了 我们用t代替s
So that's your error. But you have to also multiply it by the
这个就是 (代替产生的) 误差 接着需要把它和概率相乘
probability. Of that value appearing.
那个值出现的概率
If it never appears in your input data, then you don't care about it, because you
如果那个值在输入数据中不出现的话 就不需要再关注它了
are never going to make an error, and then you integrate over S.
因为这个值永远不会产生误差 接着才对它在s上进行积分
So, that's one equation looks how the unknowns which is the borders of our
这个方程式显示作为未知值的
interval that we are trying to find appear here.
我们寻找的区间边界
In the integral part and the representative appears here, at, so this
积分部分以及这里的代替值
is only one equation, but we can get a second equation, you can actually show
这只是一个方程 我们还可以得到第二个方程
that the S I. Are they average?
它可以表示为
Of the TI. And the TI+1.
s_i减去t_i和t_(i+1)的平均值
And that comes, because you are trying to compute the mean square error.
因为我们要计算均方误差
And that leads to average. And then from these you're going to get a
这个就会产生平均值 因而从这个就可以得到第二个方程
second equation. So you get basically two equations for
我们现在在每一个连续区间上
every one of these concatenated intervals, and you have to solve them.
就有了两个方程 接着我们要解方程
And that's not always easy. And closed solutions do not exceeds for
这并不容易 大部分的概率分布中闭合解并不存在
most of the probability distributions. But they do exist if we assume that the
但是如果我们假定概率分布是均匀的 那么闭合解确实存在
probability distribution is uniform. And that's what basically JPEG is using.
这就是JPEG使用的方程
It's saying,"Okay, okay, the product distribution is uniform so I'm just going
这就像在说 概率分布是均匀的
to just do the rounding," as I explained before.
我们只要做数值取整 像我之前说过那样
But there is good theory represented here basically in this equations that if you
但是这个方程表示了一个很好的理论
knew... The probability distribution, you can
前提是如果我们知道概率分布
actually do better than just uniform quantization.
就可以获得比均匀量化更好的效果
But once again, jpeg decided to do uniform quantization.
再说一次 JPEG使用的是均匀量化
And that's both for simplicity and also what's called universality.
为了简单起见 同样也是所谓的普遍性
I don't need to know the probability distribution.
不需要知道概率分布
I'm going to make jpeg work. Very good for basically almost any image.
就可以进行JPEG的工作 几乎对所有图像的处理效果都很好
Maybe I could have done it better for some distributions, but I'm going to just
或许在一些分布上我们的效果会更好
make it basically work for any distribution.
但是它能在所有分布上使用
And I should say to you, that you can modify JPEG, and that it's still part of
我需要告诉大家的是 大家可以修改JPEG
the standard into this your own quantisation tables.
在大家自己的量化表里 它仍然是标准的一部分
Which might follow a distribution that you know.
它或许会遵循一个你知道的分布
So if you are compressing a very particular class of images, you can
所以如果大家要压缩一类非常特殊的图像
basically tune your JPEG to do that. So with this basically, we have
可以优化出自己的JPEG来进行处理 就这些来总结一下
concluded. The basic underlying concepts of Jpeg.
JPEG的基本概念是
We start from a transform, which is DCT. We quantize uniform quantization with
从一个离散余弦变换开始 采用霍夫曼编码的均匀量化进行量化
Huffman coding. Very, very simple.
非常非常的简单
And you're going to have, as one of your optional programming exercise,
如果大家想实际创建一个JPEG作为一个可选编程的练习
to actually build JPEG. It's not going to take you long.
也不会花费大家太多的时间
If you use, for example, a software lilke MATLAB,
如果大家使用像MATLAB这样的软件
you're going to do a DCT, which is a very simple command.
如果要做离散余弦变换的话 只是一个很简单的命令
You're going to do a quantization. Remember, it's nothing other than divide,
如果要做量化 记住不外乎是除了以后再取整
round, and, if you're already playing the decoder, multiply back, by the same
然后如果准备用解码器 就相当于用相同的数乘回来
number. And then you can do a Huffman coding.
这些做完了就可以进行霍夫曼编码了
But, even without the Huffman coding, you will be able to see, when you divide by
但是即使没有霍夫曼编码 我们仍旧能够看到 当除以较大的数时
larger numbers, you basically get more compression, but, less quality.
将会得到更多的压缩 当然 质量会变低
Thank you.
谢谢大家